There's so much text in today's world,
pretty much none of us have
enough time to read all the things we
wish we had time to. So, one of
the most exciting
applications I've seen of
large language models is
to use it to
summarize text, and this is
something that I'm seeing multiple teams
build into multiple software applications.
You can do this in the chatGPT web
interface. I do this all
the time to summarize
articles so I can just kind of read
the content of many
more articles than I
previously could, and if you want to
do this more programmatically you'll
see how to in this lesson.
So with that, let's
dig into the code to
see how you could use
this yourself to summarize text. So,
let's start off with the same starter
code as you saw before
of import OpenAI, load the
API key, and here's that get
completion helper function.
I'm going to use as the running
example the task
of summarizing this
product review. Got
this panda plush toy
for my daughter's birthday, who loves
it and takes it everywhere, and so
on and so on. If you're building an
e-commerce website, and there's just a
large volume
of reviews, having a tool to summarize
the lengthy reviews could
give you a way
to very quickly glance
over more reviews to
get a better sense
of what all your customers are thinking. So,
here's a prompt for generating
a
summary. Your task is to generate a
short summary of a
product review from e-commerce
website, summarize review below, and so
on, in
at most 30 words.
And so, this is soft and cute,
panda plush toy loved by daughter,
bit small for the price,
arrived early. Not bad, it's
a pretty good summary. And
as you saw in the previous video, you
can also play with things like
controlling the character
count or the number of sentences
to affect the length of this
summary. Now, sometimes
when creating a summary, if
you have a very
specific purpose in mind
for the summary, for example, if
you want to give feedback
to the shipping department, you
can also modify the
prompt to reflect that, so
that they can generate a summary
that is more applicable to one
particular group in
your business. So, for example, if
I add to give feedback
to the shipping department, let's
say I change this to, start to
focus on any aspects that mention
shipping and delivery
of the product. And if
I run this, then, again you
get a summary, but instead
of starting off with
Soft and Cute Panda
Plush Toy, it now
focuses on the fact that it arrived a
day earlier than expected. And then
it still has, you know, other details
then.
Or as another example, if we aren't
trying to give feedback
to their shipping department,
but let's say
we want to give feedback
to the pricing department.
So the pricing department
is responsible to determine
the price of the product, and I'm
going to tell it to focus on any
aspects that are relevant
to the price and
perceived value.
Then, this generates a different
summary that it says,
maybe the price may be
too high for a size.
Now in the summaries that I've
generated for the
shipping department or
the pricing department, it
focus a bit more
on information relevant to
those specific departments. And
in fact, feel free to pause
the video now and maybe ask
it to generate information for the
product department responsible
for the customer
experience of the product, or
for something else that
you think might be
interesting to an e-commerce site.
But in these summaries,
even though it
generated the information
relevant to shipping,
it had some other information too,
which you could decide may
or may not be helpful.
So, depending on how you
want to summarize it,
you can also ask
it to extract information
rather than summarize it. So here's
a prompt that says you're tasked
to extract relevant
information to give
feedback to the shipping department. And
now it just says, product arrived
a day earlier than expected without
all of the other information, which
was also helpful in a
general summary, but less
specific to the shipping department if
all it wants to know is
what happened with the shipping.
Lastly, let me just share
with you a concrete
example for how to use this in a
workflow to help summarize
multiple reviews to make
them easier to read.
So, here are a few reviews.
This is kind of long, but you know,
here's
the second review for a standing lamp, need
a lamp on the bedroom. Here's a
third review for an
electric toothbrush. My dental
hygienist recommended kind
of a long review about the
electric toothbrush. This is
a review for a blender
when they said, so said
17p system on seasonal sale, and so
on and so on. This is
actually a lot of text. If you
want, feel free to pause the video
and read through all
this text. But what
if you want to know what these reviewers
wrote without having to
stop and read all this in detail? So,
I'm going to set review one to be
just the product review that
we had up there.
And I'm going to put all of
these reviews into a list. And
now, if I implement or loop
over the reviews, so, here's my
prompt. And here I've asked it
to summarize it in at
most 20 words. Then let's have it
get the response and print it out.
And let's run that.
And it prints out the first
review is that panda toy review,
summary review of the lamp,
summary review of the toothbrush,
and then the blender.
And so, if you have a website
where you have hundreds of reviews,
you can imagine how
you might use this
to build a dashboard
to take huge numbers of reviews,
generate short summaries of them so
that you or someone else can
browse the reviews
much more quickly. And then,
if they wish, maybe click in to
see the original longer review.
And this can help
you efficiently get a
better sense of what
all of your customers are thinking.
Right? So, that's
it for summarizing. And
I hope that you can picture, if
you have any applications with
many pieces of text, how
you can use prompts
like these to summarize
them to help people
quickly get a sense of what's in
the text, the many
pieces of text, and perhaps
optionally dig in more
if they wish.
In the next video, we'll
look at another capability
of large language models, which
is to make inferences using text. For
example, what if you had, again,
product reviews and you
wanted to very quickly get a
sense of which product reviews have
a positive or a negative sentiment?
Let's take a look at how to do
that in the next video.